Pierre Vautherin

Lead Software Engineer

I have seven years of experience in designing and developing scalable Web applications. I have a Frontend background, but I am a regular contributor to Backend as well and to Devops solutions.

p.vautherin@protonmail.com github.com/PierreVaut linkedin.com/in/pierrevautherin



Experience

SeLoger (AVIV Group) - Lead Software Engineer

Oct 2020 - present

- > Migrated local sites (Seloger, Immowelt, Logic-Immo) to a White Label solution
- > Migrated the Frontend to runtime-composition architecture using Webpack Module Federation
- > Mentoring team members & Code reviews

Photobox - Software Engineer

Nov 2018 - Oct 2020

Al-in-Editor Team

- > Contribution to AI features for Photo books creation
- > Frontend image optimization to improve speed and interactivity
- > Dynamic linking between Apps and Web experience

Groupeer Technologies - Fullstack developer (Intern)

Feb - July 2018

- > React Typescript App internationalization
- > Fleet management service for IoT devices creation

Project manager

2008 - 2017

Education

IFOCOP - 2018 - JS Fullstack Developer Training

- > frontend project: Fallout-style RPG in React
- > fullstack project: Realtime Bitcoin trading simulator

Sorbonne University - 2008 - Master's degree in Humanities

☼ Miscellaneous

Native speaker French, fluent in English.

Passionate traveller and rider. Fond of trail running.

I really love cinema, especially Kubrick, Visconti and Tarkovsky.

Languages

Typescript

HTML CSS

Libs & Frameworks

React

NextJS

Webpack / module federation

Jest / Cypress

Backend

Node

GraphQL

NestJS

Devops

AWS Lambda, ECS

CircleCI pipeline

Versionning

Git / GitHb

Project

Agile

JIRA, Confluence